

Oakville, ON, Canada

□(+1) 2892596430 | ☑ liuchew@shernet.sheridancollege.ca | # palmswill.github.io/react-resume2021/ | ☑ palmswill | 匝 williamliucs

Summary

One year React-based web developer with experiences in business management and sales campaigns on e-Commerce platforms. Passionate in designing user-friendly modern web application that make e-Commerce interaction easy and interesting for all. Currently in enhancing my skills and knowledge in Light House Lab but also open to full stack, front-end or back-end in contract or permanent position.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript ES6,HTML5,CSS3,Java

Front End Libraries & Tools: ReactJ(Router, Redux Toolkit, Context API etc), Semantic UI, Bootstrap, jQuery, SASS

Back Ends: NodeJs, Amazon S3, Google API, Firebase, Auth0, Spring Boot

Others: Data analysis, Tech Support, Database Design, Microsoft Office, ERP, Quickbook, Visual Paradigm, Figma

Projects_____

Usatex .Inc

HTTP://USATEXINC.COM/ April. 2021 - Present

- An E-Commerce website that is built for online ordering for Usatex Inc.
- · A React front end website cooperating with ERP database, Amazon S3 image cloud and auth0 authentication.

Spacetagram

HTTP://NASAPOD2021.HEROKUAPP.COM/

September,2021

- A responsive NASA picture of the day liker.
- Built with React front-end, Semantic UI & NASA POD API.

The Shoppies

HTTPS://MOVIECHALLENGE2021.HEROKUAPP.COM/

April,2021

- A shareable movie nominator website.
- Built with React front end, Semantic UI and Movie IMDB API.

Professional Experience

Tribute Window Coverings

Mississauga, Canada

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

April 2021 - Present

- · Designed and created responsive modern web applications with React that received overwhelmingly positive feedback upon launching.
- Created REST NodeJS back end interacting with Amazon S3, Gmail server, MongoDB and ERP database, allowed users to browse up to date information and communicate with the company and boosted company sales and customer satisfaction.

Taiwan Intelligence Service Corps

Taichung, S.Taiwan (Remote)

ASSOCIATE ARCHITECTURE AND SYSTEM DESIGNER(CONTRACT)

April 2019 - April 2021

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Improved performance by redesigning database and created and modify user interface.}$
- Created and modify user interface ,use cases and user flow design by communicating with the clients.
- Created detailed user manuals and release including issues and bug tracking.

Tribute Window Coverings

Mississauga, Canada

WAREHOUSE & SUPPLY CHAIN MANAGEMENT

November 2017- November 2019

- Generated daily sales and inventory report, estimated the needed purchase based on report status. Accurately predicted sales trend preventing over or shortage of stock reducing department back-order rate by 20% in 2018 compared to previous years.
- In charge of communication between vendors. Negotiated the price and brought down the cost of products for more than 10%.

Education

Lighthouse Labs Toronto, Canada

Web Development Bootcamp

Jan. 2021 - April. 2022

• Relevant topic: NodeJS, EJS, JQuery, React, PostSQL and Bootstrap

FEBRUARY 11, 2022 WILLIAM LIU · RÉSUMÉ